finding a RNN cell for the Penn Tree Bank.
This is a language modeling task and this is a benchmark for neural architecture search where you're trying to find a good RNN cell to get the perplexity really low.
And here you can see if they give the same amount of data to all the methods, then the benchmark neural architecture search is worse than the synthetic Petri dish informed architecture search.
Now, one has to say on the full data, I believe the NAO gets to about here.
But of course, if you give all of them the same data, the Petri dish beats this method.
And I think still this method here uses way more compute because it always has to evaluate all the candidates.
And that's exactly one of these where I learn an architecture to predict the other architecture by just looking at it.
So it works, but it doesn't work as well as actually running the architecture in an abstract fashion.
This also shows you the importance of selecting your experimental evaluation in a smart way.
They argue for very long why it makes sense to evaluate everything on reduced data.
such that their method here can be better and they don't have to compare to the full thing.
It's easier for them to work on reduced data and they argue, you know, it's what people usually do in practice and that's the task they focus on.
So, you know, good paper writing right here.
Yeah.