How do you, how do you actually produce training and validation data to match these?
And there are a number of ways, but what comes to mind is, is meta learning, right?
So because what you're doing, they initialize the training and validation data at random points.
So these are just random at the beginning.
And then they optimize the data itself using gradient descent.
Okay.
Now see synthetic training data and they are randomly initialized.
And they use gradient descent.
They have it somewhere.
Yes.
So they have this inner training loop, okay, which is many steps of inner training.
And then they have the outer loss, which is the, um,
It's the validation loss after the inner training loop.
And the difference from that to the true validation loss.
And then they do gradient descent on this outer loss.
Now this outer loss is a result of the inner loss.
And the inner loss is a result of the inner training procedure.
And the inner training procedure is n steps of feeding in the training data.
Every step you feed in the training data.
So your computational graph is going to look like.
So here is your training data as train.
And here are your initial parameters.
You initialize them randomly.
In the first step, you use the training data to produce theta 1.
Then in the second step, you use your training data again to produce theta 2.
And then you use it again to use data through and so on.
Each time you feed the training data in order to evolve your parameters to give you a better prediction.
So the gradient, since somewhere back here there's a loss, the gradient here will have to flow back through all of these paths and through all of these connections to the training data.
This is kind of you back propagate through an optimization procedure.
And we have this a bunch of times here.
And I've looked at the code and the code is like really crazy and it looks like proper research code, but it appears to be that that's actually what's happening.
They backprop through the optimization procedure to find this synthetic training and validation data.
Now, that's crazy, but it also kind of limits how far you can go with this, because usually you can't backprop for more than a couple of steps doing this.
Now, the fact that the inner model is small helps, but also this introduces very, very much, like these things are very brittle.
If you backprop through an optimization procedure like this, these things tend to be very brittle.
And so I think there's another thing there where you have to pay careful attention.
All right.
That's it's basically it.
The last thing they say is that they can combine this with orchid