theory of that this still works.
They compare this, of course, to the other algorithms.
They observe that their algorithm uses substantially less memory.
And well, substantially less memory and substantially less compute time.
Um, once you go up to a number of inner gradient steps and it works better than this first order mammal.
So this first order mammal was our kind of initial guess of how we could do this.
This tends to perform very poorly.
As you can see, uh, their, their, um,
Oh, you can't actually see that here.
Their method is better, but their method is better and uses less time because you have this inner conjugate gradient optimizer.
Sorry, this is the outer optimizer.
Okay.
So this is the error plot of how well are these methods are able to approximate the true gradient.
So if you could compute this true outer gradient, you know, that we did with mammal, but we optimize to the end.
How close are you getting?
Of course, the problem with this method right here is that you do these approximations.
and those could hurt you.
But the problem with mammal is that you're back propagating through the optimization procedure, and that means the non-linear errors could sort of accumulate.
And as you can see here, even though both might eventually get to the zero error, if you give them enough inner gradient steps,
Especially at the low inner gradient step regime, the implicit mammal is much better than mammal.
Now, I've just said the errors accumulate, but the effect probably here is that the fact that with mammal, you don't actually do enough inner steps to reach a good enough optimum of the inner tasks.
So these inner gradient of the tasks,
their gradients when they're still very not optimized.
And therefore they are a very bad estimate for your outer gradient than when you do more gradient steps.
So that actually hurts you more, which is also a bit surprising to me.
And then at the end you see
these conjugate gradient steps.
This is when you approximate this matrix inverse.
If you just do two steps, then at some point that error dominates.
But if you do more steps, you can reach a much lower error.
And 10 steps isn't that much for an algorithm like this.
As you can see here, the 10 steps
Your computation time will still in the regime of many gradient steps will still be lower than the original mammal.
And then they actually test this thing.
And of course, they're the best at pretty much everything.
I don't want to go into the exact details here.
I invite you to check out the paper for that, check out if you're interested in the proofs and the approximation guarantees.
And with that, bye-bye.