win-win.
So this paper is about semi-supervised learning in effect.
So it's at the intersection actually of semi-supervised learning, knowledge distillation and transfer learning.
So what do we mean by semi-supervised learning?
Usually in supervised learning you'll have some sort of data set
And the dataset will contain, let's say it's an image net, it's image dataset.
So the dataset will contain images.
This is an image with like some sort of cat on it.
And it will contain the labels according to that.
So cat.
Now, in semi-supervised learning, you assume that, so this is supervised learning.
In semi-supervised learning, you assume that only part of your dataset has the labels.
So like only this part down here has the labels, and the upper part does not have the labels.
So that's semi-supervised learning.
It's often the case when it's very expensive to get labels, so you can only get labels for a couple of images in your dataset.
But very often in semi-supervised learning, you still assume it's the same data set.
There is a slightly different setup here that's called transfer learning.
So in transfer learning, what you'll have is you'll have your data set that has the labels, but it's very small.
So you'll notice I've drawn it smaller.
That means you have very little.
That is also the case when it's very expensive to get labels, but also it's expensive to get the data itself.
This is often the case, like say in medical data, where not only is it expensive to get labels for like a CT scan, it's actually expensive to get the CT scan.
So, what the goal in transfer learning is, is to say, well, I do, I do have only this small data set, but I do have this giant other data set over here.
Now, can't I, it's not the same, it's maybe they're not CT, so these are CT scans, maybe these are x-rays, right?
They're fairly similar, similar technology.
If you slice the CT, it'll give you sort of an x-ray.
Can I pre-train my model on x-ray data and then fine-tune it on the CT data?
So that's called transfer learning, usually.
Now, this can be done with or without labels.
So it can be that for the xray dataset, you do have the labels or you don't have the labels.
There are techniques for all of those.
Now,
What we're going to look at today is kind of the situation right here.
It's the transfer learning situation where you do not have the labels for this x-ray data set.
But other than in this x-ray example, what we're going to look at is the small data set is going to be our ImageNet database, so our original picture with label database.
So you'll see immediately the difference here is that in the transfer learning setting, we usually assume that the data set we want to train on is fairly small.
Here, you know, ImageNet is already sizable.
But what we have is we have a much larger database of unlabeled images that we can just get from the internet.
So we can scrape the internet for any kind of pictures, and that will be our unlabeled dataset.
And what we'll try to do is somehow incorporate this unlabeled dataset here into the training process to get better on the ImageNet dataset.
Okay, so this is the problem statement is you have the ImageNet dataset and you have a second much larger dataset of unlabeled images and you somehow want to make use of them.
So I hope you see how this is sort of connected to the others.
It's essentially sort of a transfer semi-supervised learning setting, but with the exception that usually in transfer learning you assume that the labeled dataset is like super small.
which is not the case here.
And that's going to result in us being able to apply a different technique.
So this different technique is called the noisy student.
Now, usually what you might do in a transfer learning setting is you might want to start with that big data set, right?
Because that's the data set that's sizable enough to allow you to train a really big model on it.
And then you fine tune and you sort of hope that the information transfers over.
Here, on the other hand,