And what we want to do is we start with the ImageNet dataset.
So first, we train this in a supervised learning fashion into our model.
Now this model is going to be called the teacher model.
We know how to do this, we know how to train ImageNet models, right?
So we can train this into a teacher model that has a reasonable accuracy on the ImageNet dataset.
Step two, we're going to take that big dataset over here and use the teacher model to label the unlabeled images.
So for each image coming in here, the teacher, so maybe this is again another cat, the teacher will say, that's a cat.
Okay, so that gives you the big data set Where now you have images along with labels just the labels aren't true labels.
They're generated by the teacher and Then in the third step You train this big data set and
You train on this big data set and that's what you call your student model.
And then the student model in this paper will see how can we make it such that the student is then better at the original ImageNet task than the teacher ever was.
Which seems counterintuitive at first because all of the information that the student is trained from is basically what the teacher already knows, right?
All the labels here come from the teacher.
Therefore, the student shouldn't be able to outperform the teacher.
But in this case, the student will be able to outperform the teacher.
And their argument here is that this is mainly due to the fact that you use noise in this training procedure.
So when you train the student, what you'll do is you'll use noise.
And one of the types of noise is that you severely augment this data right here in order to train the student.
Now, we've known for a long time that data augmentation, for example, in the frameworks of self supervised learning and so on,
can have a very large benefit to training.
And here the fact that we incorporate this at extra data and we use noise and augmentations on it is going to result in a student that can sort of learn more about the data than the teacher did know.
Okay, this is basically it.
And as you can see, this is kind of their main final results, where they say, on ImageNet, our top one accuracy sort of increases right here.
And even on these kind of subsets of ImageNet, or these are sort of corrupted sets of ImageNet, they make even more substantial improvements, as you can see here.
Now we'll go into what these corrupted subsets are, but just for now, these here are very difficult variants of ImageNet.
They can be severely corrupted or distorted and so on.
And you can see that the model improves severely over the previous state of the art, which basically means that this model is more robust and that's a direct consequence of the noise.
Now one last thing I should say is that the student here is also larger than the teacher.
So that's also one thing that makes the student better.
So what you will make is the student model is larger than the teacher model as a model as the architecture.
So in combination with the noise right here, with the noise,
In combination, that means the student model is probably able to capture more of the variance of the data.
It's larger, it has more parameters, it can learn more about the data.
Together with the noise, it can probably be more robust, and that's what makes it generalize better.
And we'll also see, as we see here, it's more robust to these transformations, and it's also going to be more robust to adversarial perturbations.
So the technique