line and do that.
It's also pretty interesting the neural network that they actually used was like super duper small.
The input to the neural network consists of 84 by 84 by 4 image produced by this, so this is the pre-processing.
The first hidden layer convolves 16 8 by 8 filters with Stride 4 with the input image and applies the rectifier non-linearity, so the ReLU.
The second hidden layer convolves 32 4 by 4 filters with Stride 2, again followed by rectifier non-linearity.
The final hidden layer is fully connected and consists of 256 rectifier units.
The output layer is a fully connected linear layer with single output for each valid action.
Number of valid actions is vary between 4 and 18 on the games we considered.
Okay, as you can see, the neural network is pretty small.
It's two conv layers.
And as was in fashion back then, you had like big filters.
So you know, big filters from like AlexNet.
Yeah, big filters, but fewer than today.
So today, the trend is more like deeper layers, more filters, but they are not as big.
They're like three by three filters today only.
Pretty interesting how they did it back then.
Interesting also no max pooling and so on.