cod learning environment, if you don't know what it is, it's basically these old games right here, you can kind of emulate them and run them.
And the inputs are always sort of the same.
So you have one joystick, I believe.
So you have kind of this joystick, and it can go into various directions like left, right, up, down, and then also the intermediate directions.
And then you have a, I think also a button that you can push
And that gives you a total of some somewhere around 16 or 20 actions in each of the games.
So the good thing about this environment is that the actions are always the same.
But of course, they mean different things in different games.
So the games here, you know, for example, Pong or this breakout, these games are
kind of really low pixel games, as you can see, and they come in form of an image, right?
So this is an image.
This is like 180 pixels, and this is like 150 pixels.
And the task here is to learn a policy, which means which buttons and directions you need to push, depending on the observation right here, these pixels, and achieve the maximum amount of reward.
So reward is given in each game differently as well.
For example, in this pong game, the reward is every time you score kind of a goal against your opponent in breakout, you get a reward every time you manage to hit or kill a one of these blocks and so on.
So reward is different, but your objective is