these super high scores by pulling something off precisely.
But in games where they say where you have to plan ahead for longer, it kind of fails.
And we know that this long planning was about to be a problem for years to come, and it's still not solved.
So still Go Explorer is highly controversial that can solve these kind of long exploration games.
And
Those are still games, right?
So we are basically not, we are very much further than they were in this paper, but also we are basically nowhere yet.
Yeah, if I'm allowed to say that.
So I enjoyed reading this paper.
I, this is, it's very, it's very well written.
If you somehow know how to think about reinforcement learning, like this, this Q function, what the Q function means and why you would learn it in this way.
I find this is not super well described.
This kind of requires a bit of a knowledge of
not of RL, but just of how to think of RL.
But apart from this, everything else is written incredibly well, easy, straightforward.
And you know, this was just a nice work of its time.
And I appreciate it for that.
All right, I'll see you next time.
And I appreciate your time too.
Bye.