Hi there.
Today we'll look at playing Atari with Deep Reinforcement Learning by Vladimir Mne at All of DeepMind.
So this is another one of our series of impactful past papers.
This paper right here kicked off an entire revolution in reinforcement learning.
Specifically, it sort of started the Deep Reinforcement Learning hype.
Before that I reinforcement learning was kind of this weird field of Markov decision processes and so on.
Now I know there were successes and all and stuff was happening.
But this really made a lot of waves because it brought the power of deep neural networks.
to reinforcement learning and with a pretty simple application of convolutional networks managed to solve these reinforcement learning games where previous algorithms really couldn't either or were heavily reliant on hand engineered features.
So we'll take a look here and what people did back then, what was the state of the art and what they are telling us about that.
Kind of set it in relation to today.
Alright, if you do like papers like this, commentary like this, share it out, leave a like and tell me in the comments what you think.
So, let's dive in.
They say we present the first deep learning model to successfully learn control policies directly from high-dimensional sensory input using reinforcement learning.
The model is a convolutional neural network trained with a variant of Q-learning,
whose input is raw pixels and whose output is a value function estimating future rewards.
We apply our method to seven Atari 2600 games from the arcade learning environment with no adjustment of the architecture or learning algorithm.
We find that it outperforms all approaches on six of the games and surpasses a human expert on three of them.
So there's a lot packed into this.
First of all, I wanted to recognize the absolute Lattec savagery right here and here.
Yeah, you know, it's just something.
I'm not OCD about that kind of stuff.
I think we should ditch Lattec, honestly.
But
So there's a lot of information packed in this abstract right here.
So they say this is the first deep learning model to learn control policies.
So that's the task of these reinforcement learning algorithms directly from high dimensional sensory inputs using using reinforcement learning.
So what do they mean, these are