And the problem is fairly simple.
You want to do object detection in images.
Object detection is the task of basically, if I give you an image, you should tell me what is on the image and where.
So in this case, here, you would have to draw me this bounding box and say, this is a deer.
On the bottom, you would have to draw bounding boxes.
Maybe they have to be rectangular, maybe not and say, this is a bus.
And here is a truck and here is another truck and here is a car and so on.
So there can be many objects in an image.
There can be one object.
There can be objects of different classes or there can be no objects at all.
So this is just object detection and there have been many papers on this and specifically there has been this RCNN and this is the model that we're going to extend.
So the RCNN model or specifically the faster RCNN model that we're going to build on