they have performed very, very well.
So how does the skipgram model work?
How does it assign vectors to each word?
So first of all, it has a dictionary.
So there is a word, an input word.
And for each word, you have a big dictionary.
And the big dictionary basically says that the word two is going to be mapped to this vector point one and so on.
The word learn is going to be mapped to that vector.
And then you also have these output vectors.
right here.
And what you're trying to do is you're trying to take a phrase from the data set like this one right here.
And you take out one word like this word vector right here.
And
you're trying to frame this as a prediction task.
So you're trying to frame this as, in this case, four different prediction tasks.
So you're telling your machine, I give you the word vector, and which other words are around the word vector?
You just tell it that.
You don't tell it anything else.
You just say which other words are around the word vector.
And the correct answers in this case would be to learn word and representations.
So this you construct four different training examples where you have an x and a y. So the x is always vector and the y is 2.
And then the next training sample the x is vector.
and the y is learn and so on.
So this here, each training sample is a classification task.
And the classification task is, as you can see,
No, you can't see right here.
But the classification task is you have the input word and you classify it into one of many, many, many, many, many, many, many classes.
Namely, there are as many classes as you have words in the dictionary.
So each word in the dictionary will have a class associated with it.
So in ImageNet, you have like a thousand classes, but in these, that's already a lot, but in these tasks, you're going to have a hundred thousand classes because there are a hundred thousand words in the English language that you want to treat.
And there are many more, but in this case, they leave away all the words that appear less than five times in their corpus.
That's still a lot of words.
So it's like a super-duper-duper lot of a classification task.
But ultimately, if you do something like this, then the representation that you end up with is going to be very, very good at doing these kind of downstream tasks.
And that's what they discovered.
So their skipgram model is nothing else than taking a word and predicting the surrounding words from that word.
And this is what it means.
This is the formal statement of the skipgram objective.
What you want to do is the objective of the skipgram model is to maximize the average log probability, this one.
So for the word we're considering the word T,
We want to maximize the log probability of each word W that is around the word C, sorry, around the word W in a context window of C. That's exactly what we did before.
We take a word like this model right here and from it, we predict all of the words around it in a given window, right?
That's all.
That's the entire objective.
And that will give you very good representations.
And this is how you would implement that.
So what you'll have is you'll have these vector representation V that comes from your original dictionary.
Those are the things you learn.
And then because you have like an 30,000 way classifier, you know that a classification layer is nothing else than a linear layer followed by a softmax operation.
And that linear layer also has parameters.
These are the V primes.
Okay.
So first you have the look up in the dictionary for the word vector right here.
And this is the vector of the classification layer.
Now there are modifications where you can use like the same vectors and so on, or you can also make use of these vectors.
But ultimately you care about these vectors right here.
And the vectors here are simply the classification layers weights.
So here you can see that there is what you're trying to maximize is the inner product between the word that you're considering and the words around that word.
And you're trying to do a classification task.
So you need to normalize.
Now this is the normalization constant and it goes over all of your vocabulary.
So that's what they tackle here.
They say W is the number of words in the vocabulary.
This formulation is impractical because the cost of computing the gradient is proportional to W, which is often large.
And that's 10 to the five to 10 to the seven terms.
So many, like tens of millions of terms in your vocabulary.
That's just not feasible, right?
So people have been sort of trying different ways to get around very, very large number of classes.
And here it seems that that is really our bottleneck.
In the previous paper, they've already shown that this objective can give you very good word representation.
But now we need to get around the fact