Hi there.
Today we'll look at distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality by Thomas Mikolov, Ilya Sotskyver, Kai Chen, Greg Corrado and Jeffrey Dean.
This is another historical paper.
It's one of three papers.
It's the middle one that introduces the original word-to-vec algorithm.
And if you, as you might know, word-to-vec
was extremely influential in NLP since this paper, basically until recently, where it's sort of gone out of fashion a bit in research with the rise of things like Elmo and Bert, but it's still very, very relevant.
So we'll look at this historical paper today with kind of the hindsight of being a couple years into the future, in fact,
as you see right here.
This was released in 2013.
So it's seven years later now.
And we'll look back and we'll see what they said back then about the system.
This is not going to be like a very, you know, well-enhanced PowerPointy presentation of how we're to vex
works.
We're going to look at the paper and read it together.
If you like content like this, if you like historical paper readings, let me know in the comments.
Share it out if you do like it.
And of course, subscribe, because these kind of historical papers, I enjoy them, but many people might already know what these things are.
So yeah.
Okay, let's, you know, go through the paper and pick up their ideas and kind of put them in context.
They say the recently introduced continuous skip gram model is an efficient method for learning high quality distributed vector representations that capture a large number of precise syntactic and semantic