And so on.
So the question, of course, is how do you train this model?
How do you train a model that gives you good candidates for subdivision?
And the answer here comes from the idea of hindsight experience replay.
So let's say, again, you are here and you want to go here.
And you're not very good at it initially.
So they train this model, as I understand, along with letting their agent act in this environment.
So the agent uses the model to plan, but initially it's not very good.
So maybe the agent will fail a lot of times.
So instead of going to the blue square, it will reach this white square right here.
It will go here here and here who reached the white square instead of saying I failed what you can do and this is the idea of hindsight experience replay is.
To say well I did fail but I did reach something right I have reached a thing.
And it's actually possible that that thing could have been the goal, but this particular episode, this was the goal.
Remember, the goal changes every time.
It's a goal directed policy.
So it says, well, this could have been the goal, possibly.
So if I just pretend this was the goal, then I have a training example for a successful run.
So the hindsight experience replay basically pretends that what you
have achieved, even if you failed, was your actual goal.
And that gives you a positive training example for an episode with that as a goal.
And it could have been the goal because the goal is chosen at random.
So this gives you a good training example.
Now this paper just generalizes the hindsight experience replay or applies it to their particular framework.
And they say, well, if I reach this thing, that means
Any point on this path is a good candidate for subdividing the path, because I did actually reach the point.
Remember, the goal is to propose a point where your foreshore are going to pass through.
Now, since I've taken this path to this goal, I have passed through any of the squares in between, and so these are my possible sub-candidates.
And all other black squares, I don't want that.
So now I have a classifier I can train, I can say any of these squares on my path are good squares to subdivide and any not on my path are bad ones.
They go a step further, I believe, and they actually say we're, so if this was m steps, we're actually going to take the particular square that is reached after m half steps.
So the exact middle point of that path is going to be our,
training example for subdivisions.
So you have a classifier that has exactly one target to train.
So this you train along with acting in the environment.
And of course, your model for proposing subdivisions is going to be better and better and better and better.
And that makes your planning algorithm better and better, and that makes you collect better episodes.
And so you can sort of bootstrap yourself up this thing.
Now, this is the basic experiment of the paper.
They also do this in a 3D manner, where they move this little spider here around.
So the spider was trained to just move from one block to the next block, and the planner basically has to tell it where to go.
And they show that they outperformed the traditional Monte Carlo tree search.
Now, I have to say this is cool, but you have to remember this is only advantageous in very, very specific types of problems.
So first of all, it has to be this goal-directed nature.
Otherwise, you probably couldn't train this predictor here super well.
Then, given that you have such a good predictor, the problem needs to be such that
If you have a start state, there could be many ways to go about reaching the end.
And if you have an end state, there could be many ways from where you could come from.
But there is some bottleneck state in the middle where you're pretty sure that you're going to have to pass through it.
If your problem is of that nature, if it has these bottleneck states where you can predict with reasonable accuracy that you're going to have to pass through, then this is a good algorithm to consider.
is intuitively outperforming the original Monte Carlo tree search because you have much less deep search tree and you can effectively limit its width by using that model.
They also have made this website where they show videos of their spider and
I haven't seen it in a while, but it is, it is like next to the mouse.
If you can see it.
So, so you, you see, this is kind of a continuous control problem that also requires planning.
And they also have these kind of gifts of how they're, they're, what order their plans are constructed in.
So I invite you to check this out, read the paper.
Uh, if you like this, uh, subscribe, leave a like, leave a comment, and thank you for listening.
Bye-bye.