in divide and conquer Monte Carlo tree search.
You're not searching over actions.
You are searching over the best way to subdivide this problem, right?
You're searching over which of these all the black squares should I use to subdivide my problem into sub-problems, and that's what you build your search tree from.
So naturally, you can already see what kind of possibilities do we have here to subdivide this problem.
I drew one white square, but any of the black squares are candidates to subdivide this problem, right?
Any of the black squares could be potential subdivisions.
And this is what we search over.
So in Monte Carlo tree search, we search over the actions, which gives us this four to the D tree.
But in divide and conquer,
we're searching over all the ways to subdivide the problem.
And as you can see there, that are many, many more possibilities.
So from this first starting node, we have like, like a hundred possibilities to subdivide this problem into two problems, right?
And each of those, again, if you now