And what they do, of course, is they use deep learning as you might have guessed to do that.
So they will have a model that for a particular start and end goal will give them a probability distribution across candidates.
Now, everything that's black here also has probability mass, but it's just so small you can't see.
And these blue ones are the lighter blue, the more probable this model thinks that this is going to be an in-between state.
Now the tree search can now limit itself effectively to only the ones here with the highest probability, right?
So we select the ones with the highest probability and we'll only search plans that have these as the first possible subdivisions.
Again, we're searching over plans.
So we're searching over ways to subdivide the problem into smaller problems.
That is our search space.
So once we've decided on one of them, let's say here the yellow one, again, we have to evaluate that model for each of the sub problems.
And this, this is kind of a step that's missing here.
So in between here, there would be a model evaluation that would again tell you which of these in between states were probable subdivision candidates.
and then you would select again one of those in that particular search branch.
And in a different search branch, you're searching over these things, in a different search branch you would select a different one and see is this possibly a better way to subdivide the problem.