you've decided on a subdivision.
Let's say you decided on this one right here.
You say, I want to pass through that point on my way to the goal.
Now you have to subdivide that in this sub problem into two problems.
Again, every possible black square.
I'm not saying which one is a good thing to subdivide the problem.
I'm just asking what is a possible candidate.
every single black square here is a possible candidate for a path from here to here.
And again, for this particular subproblem, you have to do the same thing.
So the search tree here, even though we said before, this one is very deep, and this one is probably only log 2D deep,
its width is going to be enormous and