speech.
Text-to-speech is basically you take a piece of text, like this one, modern text-to-speech synthesis, pipelines typically involved, blah, blah, blah, and you want to make a model that takes this and outputs sound waves as if a human would say it, right?
So either modern text to speech and so on.
Now, I have multiple problems when doing this.
First of all, the text here is words.
Let's say we can tokenize the text into words.
So you have modern text to speech.
Those are four tokens.
However, sound waves are, of course, much, much densely sampled.
So these sound waves, they are typically in the order of something like 24 kilohertz sampled.
So that's the ratio of one token to output samples is super high.
So one token will produce many, many thousand samples in the speech.
So that's the first problem.
The second problem is that if you have training data, so you have data that has a piece of text and you have the sound wave that a human, you know the human read that particular piece of text.
You still don't know which word exactly corresponds to which portion of that text.
You simply know the entire text corresponds to the entire sound wave.
You don't know this word text right here.
You don't know.
You don't know where it starts and where it ends in this sound wave.
And the last problem you obviously have is that you want to make this in a way that it generalizes, that it sounds like a human, but also generalizes to some other text.
And this paper here solves all of these problems jointly by doing an adversarial approach to learning.