Let's look at the discriminators because that's the easiest.
So they have these discriminators and these are adopted from this GAN TTS paper.
Now, as we already said, the discriminator try to differentiate between real and fake sound and they do it in a sort of
So if they were to just look at the entire sound wave, then it would just basically reduce to comparing the two.
But instead, the discriminators, they operate on very small windows.
So in specific, they have five different discriminators, and each of the five different discriminators take a different size window length.
But all of these windows are super short.
So one discriminator might take this long windows.
Another discriminator might take a bit longer windows, and another discriminator might take a bit shorter windows.
And that, of course, from the real and from the fake.
And the discriminators simply try to discriminate only in these windows, whether it's real or fake.
And now we're a bit more into the GAN setting, where you simply have one data point of the real and one data point of the fake, and you have to compare them.
And this here, I believe, is one of the keys why this model generalizes, because the discriminators basically they try to assess whether a short sequence sounds like real or sounds like fake, and whether the two samples sound alike in different scales of time.
And by only doing this on these short scales, the loss sort of generalizes.
Otherwise, if you compare it on the entire sound wave, it would just reduce to comparing point by point right here.
And if the generator produces something that's not exactly aligned, then of course every point would be wrong.
You run into all sorts of questions.
So this is a set of five discriminators that all try to take each takes a different length of subsound of this wave tries to discriminate real from fake.
That's the discriminator loss.
They have an additional discriminator loss where they compute spectrograms of these things.
So
Spectrograms and compute spectrogram of this and they have a discriminator and other neural network here that it tries to distinguish which one is real and which one is fake note that this is not the same as down here where the spectrogram is an intermediate representation.
Here the sound is the output and from the sound you compute the spectrogram and then you compare the two.
So this is simply a different, the spectrogram is a different feature space for the discriminator to compute the loss.
It is not an intermediate representation on the way to produce the sound itself.
So that's the difference here between the classic approach and this approach.
So it's end-to-end adversarial.
So we got the discriminator.
The discriminators simply try to differentiate the sound waves and short scales as well as the spectrograms.
Now the second part is of course the general