In this work, we take on the challenging task of learning to synthesize speech from normalized text or phonemes in an end-to-end manner, resulting in models which operate directly on character or phoneme input sequences and produce raw speech audio outputs.
Okay, that wasn't the real model.
I just thought it sounded really funny.
This is a text-to-speech model, and it actually sounds like this.
In this work, we take on the challenging task of learning to synthesize speech from normalized text or phonemes in an end-to-end manner, resulting in models which operate directly on character or phoneme input sequences and produce raw speech audio outputs.
Okay.
Now, you've probably, if you have listened to the text and not just how the text sounds, you have gotten what this paper is about.
So the paper is called End to End Adversarial Text to Speech by Jeff Donoway, Sander Diehlmann, Mikolaj Binkowski, Eric Elson, and Karen Simonian of, I believe, of mostly deep mind.
And this paper on a high level, it produces speech, so sound, the sound waves of speech directly from text or from what they call normalized text or phoneme text.
And it does so without any intermediate supervised representations.
And that's a challenging task.
And the main problems here are the alignment problem that they have to solve and actually making, making this work in an adversarial manner.
So, we're going to look at this paper.
As always, if you like work like this, consider subscribing and sharing it out.
And if you have any comments, leave them in the comment section.
Okay, so what's the problem with text