it does it end to end.
Now adversarial simply means that you have a generator that takes in the piece of text right here and generates this sound wave and then you have a discriminator that looks at this sound wave and it looks at the real sound wave.
So the real
Okay, the real sense, let's say this over here is real, and this is what the generator has produced, the discriminator tries to discriminate between the two.
Now, this is not entirely the same thing as a supervised loss.
Usually in a GAN, you do not have the corresponding samples, right?
You simply input a real sample here,
and the generator produces a generated sample here.
You do not necessarily have in a classic GAN the corresponding sample.
Here you assume that you have the corresponding real sample, but it's still different than supervised learning in that both go through a discriminator and the discriminator tries to tell, the discriminator is a neural network, tries to tell which one is real and which one is generated.
In fact, the discriminator is a set of neural networks that we're going to go into that shortly.
So it's adversarial in the sense that there is a generator and a discriminator.