Okay.
So how do they do it?
Via what they call trajectory, via regularization of trajectory optimization.
So in essence, what do we want to regularize here?
There are many things we could do to solve this, but the way this paper goes is they say we not only do we want the most return, we also
want a high log probability of our taken path.
So this here, as you can see, this is observation action and so on, observation action.
So this is the future.
This right here is the future.
So this, this sequence here is going, is what is going to give me the reward right here.
Right.
So G is also dependent on these things, but it's not said explicitly here.
So G is dependent on your plan or maybe let's not call this the future.
This is the plan.
Okay.
This is the plan you came up with.
So this is directly going to influence G and G is the reward you're going to get under your model.
But also you want the log probability of the plan itself to be high.
Now there, I think there is a bit, there is something missing here and that is conditioned on your training distribution right here.
And I think that's a actually a rather crucial part.
No, that's, that's the KL thing.
So this is conditioned on your training.
So what you want is you want the plan to be basically in your training distribution.
So you want your plan that you're going to execute if that is actually part of your training data set.
then you know I have already executed this once before and it's reasonable to assume that therefore my world model has learned from this experience and is going to give me an accurate reward.
If we go back to our rooms example then
up here somewhere.
If we go back to our room's example, you see that anywhere in the green area where I have already explored, the world model is fairly good.
It's going to give me accurate reflection of the world, but as soon as I go outside the green area, it is not.
And inside the green area is basically where my training data is.
Now, if I in the future actually take a path here, crash into a wall right here, right?
You saw in the algorithm, at the end of an episode, I'm going to add my trajectory to the training data for the world model.
So this green part here expands to include that.
And now, if I go here again,
If my plan goes there again, now I can trust the world model, but also now it has, it is actually correct because it has a wall here.
So you see that the regularization basically, not only do I want the biggest reward possible under my world model, I also want that the plan that I'm about to execute is, has a high probability under my training distribution.
Okay.
And the way we do this is by denoising auto-encoders.
So I want the log probability here to be high and you do this via a denoising autoencoder.