Okay, now here is the algorithm, as you can see, this was already quite the algorithm we use nowadays.
So for K steps, this is the inner maximization, and here they say that we use K equals one.
So this is pretty much what we use today.
The early days of GAN were still like, how much do I need to discriminate per generator and so on.
Nowadays everyone's just using one step here, one step there, or even training and jointly works in some cases.
So you want to sample a mini batch of noise samples, and then you will sample a mini batch of m examples from training data generation.
So from this data, you want to update the discriminator by ascending its stochastic gradient.
And this is simply the gradient of the objective.
And then after those case steps you want to sample another mini batch of noise samples and update the generator by descending its stochastic gradient.
And you can see right here already there is this reduced objective that doesn't include this because it falls away in the gradient, right?
And they say the gradient based updates can use any standard learning based rule.
We use momentum in our experiments.
Very cool.
So I believe they already also say that.
It is somewhere here.
It's pretty fun that they say, oh, in our generator, we only input noise at the lowest layer.
This is also something that, if you think that G here is a multi-layer network, so it's kind of a multi-layer network that outputs an image.
And if you ask yourself, if I have noise, how would I input that into there?
It's so clear nowadays that, you know, we just put it here.
But this was not clear at all.
This was kind of an invention of this paper because you could, you know, put it pretty much at all layers.
You could distribute it and so on.
You could add some right here.
It was this paper that already established the fact that we input noise kind of as a vector at the very beginning and then just let the neural network produce the image from that.
So yeah, pretty, pretty cool.
It's pretty sneaky how many things are hidden in these initial papers, how many decisions that are made there then are just taken over.
And, you know, this one, I guess turned out to be fairly, fairly good.
Okay.