in GAN variations.
They introduced the reasoning behind this so that there's an intuition right here.
And you can see already, in practice, equation one may not provide sufficient gradient for G to learn well.
Early in learning when G is poor, D can reject samples with high confidence because they're clearly different from the training data.
In this case, this saturates rather than training G to minimize that, we can train G to maximize log D. This objective function results in the same fixed point for the dynamic, but provides much stronger gradients in early, much stronger gradients early in learning.
This is in contrast to like other papers that simply say, oh, we do this and they at least say it provides the same fixed point, right?
Yeah, so again, they're trying to convince you that this is doing something useful and that this is easier.
Okay.
So this strategy is analogous to other things training, maintain samples, um, from a Markov chain from one learning step in the next order to avoid burning in a Markov chain in another loop of learning.
Sorry.
Okay.
This is from another paper.
So their point here is that it's analogous.
to other papers that use these Markov chains where you always do one step in G and one step in D. We alternate between K steps of optimizing D and one step of optimizing G because you have this inner maximization over D and then the outer maximization, outer minimization over G.
So this has already been around the fact that you kind of have to have these optimizations in lockstep.
But the difference here is you don't need any sort of like Markov chain in the inner loop and so on.
You simply need back propagation.
So here's an illustration of how that might
work.
So at the beginning here, you have your Z space, and this is always sampled uniformly, as you can see right here.
This is from a prior distribution.
And through the mapping, so this here is from Z to X is G. So this is the mapping G. You can see that the uniform distribution is now mapped to something non uniform, which results in the green thing.
So G is the green line.
while as this is data, the black dots are data.
And if you have a discriminator, the discriminator is supposed to tell you where there's data and where there's fake data.
Now, so green here is fake.
Now this blue line is sort of a half trained discriminator.
Now you train D, right?
You maximize D the discriminator, and that gives you this blue line right here.
So this is a perfect discriminator for these two data distributions.
It tells you it's basically the ratio of green to black at each point.
And now you train the generator according to this.
And you can see that the gradient of the discriminator is in this direction.
So it's like up this hill.
And that's why you want to shift your green curve over here according to the gradient of the discriminator.
Note that we first trained the discriminator and now in a second step we optimize the generator.
So now we shift this green curve over in order to along the gradient of the blue curve.
So it's important the green curve doesn't see the black curve ever.
The generator doesn't see the data.
The generator simply sees that blue curve and it goes along the gradient of that blue curve of the discriminator.
Okay.
And then if you do this many, many steps, actually there are dots right here, you will end up with a discriminator that has no clue what's where this is one half probability everywhere because the ratio is the same.
And you will end up with the probability of data equal to the probability of the output generated samples.
And this can happen if the generator simply remembers the training data.
But there are a number of things that counter that.
For example, the generator is continuous while the training data is, of course, discrete.
So there is this in-between things right here where there is no training data.
In fact, to hit exactly training data is very, very unlikely.
But of course, you can still peek at the training data.
But also, I think there are two things why the generator doesn't simply remember the training data first because it doesn't ever see the training data directly.
So it can only see it through the discriminator.
And second of all, because it is built as these multi-layer neural networks, it doesn't have the power to just remember this because as there is kind of this notion of continuous function.
So, and the, these neural networks are rather smooth functions often.
And therefore I think that is something that helps the generator avoid remembering the training data.
Of course, there is still this problem of mode collapse that was really big in GANs.
So even if it doesn't remember the training data, it might focus on the easiest part of the training data and forget all other parts.
And that was a direct result, actually, of this objective.
So where was it?
So this objective directly led to mode collapse in some form because it penalizes different errors differently.
Of course, people have come up with ways to solve that.