All right, let's dive in.
So vision transformers are a new thing, right?
Vision transformers.
I've also made a video about vision transformers.
They are the easy, the simple application of the transformer architecture, which was
prevalent in natural language processing with the introduction of attention is all you need and follow up papers, BERT and so on.
And applying this to images.
And the concept is very simple.
You have an image and you divide this into patches.
So you divide the image into patches.
And then you simply unroll that array sort of.
So you unroll that array.
So you have patch, patch, patch, patch, and so on.
And then you simply consider this as a sequence, like a sentence, like, Hello, my name is, and so on.
you simply consider the sequence of patches as word embeddings.
So there's like one, I think there is one fully connected layer to actually get the word embedding or the token embedding.
And then you put a transformer as you would in an LP.
So there is a transformer
here.
And you do whatever you do with a transformer.
So usually, if you don't know, people prepend a special token, that special token is usually called something where I might not draw this, that special token is usually called CLS token.
And that is also passed through the transformer and the transformer in its base configuration.
It keeps the length of the sequence the same.
It's actually not necessary to do this, but that's just how we do things.
So for every input token, you'll get a corresponding output token or output embedding or output signal, whatever you want to call it.
And such that none of the input tokens is, you know, kind of preferred because every input token sort of refers to some little patch here in the image.
If you want to say something about the entire image, you don't want to prefer any one of them.
So what you do is you have this special token, the CLS token.
which is associated with no location in the image.
And that's ultimately what you use to classify the image or also here to do representation learning.
So the representation we're looking to get out is the final layer embedding of the CLS token.
And that through the transformer architecture had aggregated all the information or we hope so from all the visual tokens in the image.