But now it breaks down because the teacher is constructed from the student.
So we have a teacher, we train the student to predict the same thing as the teacher does, like learning from the teacher.
But then at the same time, after we have done after we've updated the student, we then
have we then build the teacher from the new student.
And the way we do this you can see right here is by exponentially moving average.
So we keep the teacher model and then as we update the student model we simply update the teacher a little bit into the direction of the student model.
And there is also a schedule associated with this exponentially moving average like how much the exponential decay is and so on.
This seems all to be loaded with hyperparameters, but again, the results are really cool.
And I guess it's yet going to turn out how sensitive to hyperparameters this whole setup is.
They do make ablations, but we'll see how other people with other datasets fare.
Alright, so we have the teacher that is built from the student exponentially moving average.
And we want to make the two predict the same represents or the same output for different augmentations of the same image.
Okay, in fact,