the paper we started with the notion of info states and info states are kind of like states in classic reinforcement learning and we determined that we can't really use the sort of alpha zero way of doing things because the value of info states not only depends on downstream things but also on upstream things and the values here yeah that makes the values at the end of the tree not constant
And that means we can't really use that as we saw in this poker thing.
Then we converted the game from an info state representation to a public belief state representation, where now it's again a everyone knows everything game.
Therefore, we could use the alpha zero way of doing things.
However, since these states and the actions are so large because it consists of these giant tables of numbers, we can't use the alpha zero for computational reasons.
Luckily, they find a way to connect
the value function of public belief states to the value functions of info states and therefore we can use a solver in the classic in the discrete representation to approximate or to
to use in this search procedure, as long as we run it multiple times and sort of keep updating its values.
By doing that, we can use this in this self play, simply iteratively doing this in each step, and
We can use bootstrapping and play, as we said, self-play between two agents, and that will provably converge to a good value function and to an ash equilibrium.
All right, that was the paper.
Thanks for listening.
I'll see you next time.
Bye-bye.