They also do scale invariant fine-tuning where if they fine-tune, which is where you take this model you trained with mask language modeling and then you fine-tune it to NLP tasks, they have a bunch of tricks there like virtual adversarial training and normalizing the embeddings before they do that and that apparently helps a lot.
But they also say they leave the comprehensive study of this for future work.
For now, they just want to get the good number.
And which is understandable because you get published.
Um, all right.
So here you can see, uh, actually we can, we can skip most of the tables.
They are better.
They're better in language modeling too, which is interesting.
So you can do kind of bird style denoising, but in classification, you can also do actually other regressive language model, which is pretty cool.
So here they do an ablation study of the different components where they remove this enhanced the decoder.
And one time they remove the content to position encodings.
Sorry attention mechanism and one time they reduce the position to content attention mechanism and in the table it is sort of A wash depends on the task of how you look at but each of the components here gets you some kind of a benefit or a hit when you take it away so
Yeah, it's not really clear that one of the components gives you all the boost.
The combination of them is obviously the best and it's really cool when papers do these kinds of ablations rather than just throw a bunch of stuff at you and it's on you to figure out which of that stuff is
important.
They compare it to Roberta in terms of training of accuracy after training.
So how much do you need pre-training for a fine-tuning and the diberta as you can see in these graphs outperforms Roberta.
So potentially you need less pre-training steps to reach the same accuracy in
fine-tuning task which is cool also means that if you train for longer you reach or if you train for the same amount of time you reach a higher accuracy.