Hi there, today we'll look at deburta, decoding enhanced BERT with disentangled attention by Peng Chenghe, Xiaodong Liu, Zhang Fenggao, and Waiju Zhen of Microsoft.
This paper is an improvement on BERT, the language model and the Roberto variant of it.
Specifically, it suggests two improvements, namely,
First is this disentangled attention where they disentangle positional information and content information of the individual tokens in the attention mechanism.
And the second improvement is kind of results from the first improvement as this decoding enhanced decoder, I guess enhanced decoder.
where because they only use relative positional information in the transformer part of the model, they have to re-feed the absolute positional information at the end, which gives them another bit of improvement.
All together with this, they reach state-of-the-art in various NLP tasks, and this model, Deberta, is now available in Huggingface for you to download for all of your NLP needs.
So we're going to go through the paper and look at the two improvements and what they give.
Let's see if that's relevant.
As always, if you like content like this, don't hesitate to share it out to all of your friends and leave a like and a comment.
I still read all the comments, so give me your opinion.
And please also give me your opinions on the new recording setup.
There should be a title somewhere here, a picture somewhere here.
I absolutely want to hear feedback because I have no idea what I'm doing.
So, yeah.
All right, let's dive in Deberta or Deberta or Deberta.
I don't know.
I think it's Deberta because it's from decoding enhanced.
Deberta is a new model architecture they say here.
We propose a new model architecture Deberta, decoding enhanced BERT with disentangled attention that improves the BERT and ROBERTA models using two novel