all of it.
Okay.
All right.
And the rest is, is just like classic attention.
Okay.
Now you, you simply, so these P and H matrices are obtained by
Sorry, the queries and the keys for this are obtained by linear transformation.
So you see this is the incoming signal.
You send it through a linear transformation to obtain the queries, and you also send it through a linear transformation to obtain the keys.
So the H is the same, but these matrices here, these are learned weights to produce queries and keys.
And then you multiply them together.
That defines your attention matrix.
You run that through a softmax to make a distribution out of each row.
And then you multiply together with the values.
So this part here is kind of like the routing table and the values are the information to be routed.
The values are obtained from these input signal.
As we said, we're going to amend that by, so this over here is the classic key queries, keys and values.
Sorry, that's too much.
The classic queries, keys and values.
And then we augment that by two new.
So there is the queries and the keys for the position.
And you can see that the difference here is that, again, it's learned weights, but now there is this P thing right here.
And the P is positional encodings, and that comes exactly out of this table we saw up here.
So the positional encodings come from this.
And it's important to see that this here is h and this is the p values.
But this is only h0, right?
h is actually transformed to h1 by the transformer, the first layer, to h2 by the second layer, and so on.
The p always stays the same.
So you would feed the P into this layer, and you would feed it again into this layer, and you would feed it again into this layer.
So you can see it's only positional information.
It's not content information.
And by feeding the position each time and doing this in this disentangled way,
the model can sort of keep the content and position information separate.
I actually think it doesn't really keep the information separate because after layer one, you certainly have position information in your H, right?
You can see that from this path here, from the actually feeding position information into the transformer layer, H one is already going to be
a conglomerate of H0, which is pure content, plus the position somehow.
This plus is not a real addition, but somehow the information is intermingled there.
And if we weren't to feed in these things right here, it would just be like the classic BERT, right, what they criticize.
Now by continuously feeding the positional information,
That is one advantage.
You can actually do that with BERT.
You can just add the position information each time.
I'm not sure if that would work super well, but you can do that.
It just gives the model a bit more side information to work with.
And then by keeping it separate,
Yeah, as I said, I'm not I'm not sure it's actually separate.
It's just that you keep feeding in position information layer after layer, therefore giving the model sort of more information every time it makes a transformation, because otherwise it would have to carry through the position information through all the layers, just from the very first layer.
Okay.
So in this mechanism, you can see it's true that the position encoding is kept separate because it comes in fresh every layer.
But I don't, I don't see that the content, the content certainly has position information in it from the last layer.
I hope you can, you can see that.
So